# **AUDREY J. BARE**

210 Kilgannon Lane, Lancaster, PA 17603 Cell: (717) 578.5394 Email: audrey.bare@gmail.com

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Dedicated and hard-working educator who learns quickly and develops strong working relationships. Experience with program management, leadership development, workshop facilitation, and career and school counseling. Proficient with Microsoft Office Products, PC and MAC applications, and social media platforms.

## **INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE**

# School Counseling Intern (January 2013-present)

George Washington Elementary School, School District of Lancaster

- Counseled students in grades 1 through 5 to address issues related to behavior, academic performance, work habits, and/or mental health
- Met with a caseload of 15 students weekly, helping them develop individual performance goals and healthy coping strategies for addressing a variety of issues
- Led small groups weekly on topics such as relational aggression, relationships, and conflict resolution
- Observed IEP meetings, Student Assistance Team Meetings, and classroom lessons on topics such as bullying and self-esteem

## **School Counseling Intern** (January 2013-present)

Southern Middle School and Susquehannock High School, Southern York County School District

- Conducted classroom observations for 10 students in grades 7 and 8 who had been identified for potential academic and emotional support services
- Counseled 10 students in grade 12 to discuss future academic and vocational goals
- Created and administered a pre-survey and post-survey for each individual career counseling session to assess students' learning and prepared a presentation of survey results
- Observed IEP meetings, Administrative Team Meetings, and small groups on topics such as anger management and conflict resolution
- Served as a proctor for the ACT, AP exams, and Keystone Exams

#### RELATED EXPERIENCE

## **Graduate Assistant** (July 2012-present)

Office of Experiential Learning and Career Management (ELCM), Millersville University, Millersville, PA

- Meet with students individually to critique resumes and provide career coaching
- Match students with internship opportunities for academic credit in the Lancaster area
- Deliver workshops for various courses and student organizations relevant to career planning, networking, and using social media in the job search
- Help organize and facilitate events for ELCM, including Career Week, Job and Internship fairs, Volunteer Fairs, and Teacher Recruitment Day

#### **Guest Teacher** (October 2010-June 2012)

Lincoln Intermediate Unit (LIU), New Oxford, PA

- Serve as a substitute teacher for LIU's Special Needs programs, as well as the Dallastown, Central, West York, Southwestern, Red Lion, and Hanover area school districts
- Trained in classroom management techniques and differentiating instruction for diverse learners

# **Program Associate** (July 2007-March 2010)

Delaware Academy for School Leadership (DASL), University of Delaware, Newark, DE

- Supervised the work of seven graduate assistants and three undergraduate interns
- Helped design the curriculum and planned and managed all sessions for the Aspiring Leader Development Program, a leadership training program for 50 teachers
- Helped design the curriculum and planned and managed all sessions for the Coaching and Mentoring Program, a statewide training program for 40 first-year school leaders
- Planned and managed the curriculum and logistics for all sessions of the Vision 2015 Executive Leadership Academy, a four-month professional development training program for 100 school administrators and teacher leaders
- Coordinated the 2007-08 Administrative Supply Survey and the 2007-08 Teacher Retention Survey
- Helped plan a professional development training program for 60 educational professionals from Tobago
- Participated in three follow-up site visits in Tobago to monitor program implementation
- Coordinated several statewide conferences, including Delaware's 2007 Teacher Retention Conference, and the 2008 Conference on Teaching, Leading, and Influencing Learning Conditions
- Certified Implications Wheel Facilitator and McREL Balanced Leadership trainer
- Managed payroll for 40 retired school leaders serving as program facilitators and managed payroll for graduate students and undergraduate interns
- Managed budgets totaling approximately \$20,000-\$60,000 for various programs

## **Legislative Intern** (September 2006-June 2007)

Delaware Department of Education, Dover, DE

- Represented the Department of Education in the Delaware General Assembly
- Prepared position papers on educational-related legislation for the Secretary of Education's office

## **Research and Evaluation Intern** (June-August 2006)

Red Clay Consolidated School District, Wilmington, DE

- Created evaluation tools for district-wide implementation of an online instructional management system, including: program logic model, pre and post-surveys, and professional development cluster plan
- Assisted with the design of a district plan for a professional development school (involving a partnership with the University of Delaware)

## **Graduate Research Assistant** (June 2005-June 2007)

Institute for Public Administration, University of Delaware, Newark, DE

- Researched and analyzed teacher recruitment and retention issues in Delaware
- Followed up with presentations of findings to superintendents and personal directors
- Implemented policy recommendations and training workshops concerning hiring and retention issues

## **EDUCATION**

Millersville University, Millersville, PA

Master of Education in School Counseling, May 2014

GPA: 3.8/4.0

Honors: Graduate Tuition Scholarship and Stipend (2012-2014)

**Activities:** Millersville University Peer Tutoring Program, American School Counselors Association (ASCA), Pennsylvania School Counselors Association (PSCA), Lancaster County School Counselors Association (LCSCA)

University of Delaware, Newark, DE

Master of Arts in Public Administration, May 2007

**Specialization:** Educational Policy **Study Abroad:** Scotland and the Netherlands **GPA:** 3.9/4.0

**Honors:** Graduate Tuition Scholarship and Stipend (2005-2007), Pauline E. Loessner Memorial Scholarship (2006), United Alumni for Urban Affairs Student Award (2007), Study Abroad Scholarship (2007)

**Activities:** Pi Alpha Alpha National Honor Society, School of Urban Affairs Student Association, Newark Day Nursery and Children's Center Board Member, Catholic Youth Organization Basketball Coach

University of Delaware, Newark, DE **Honors Bachelor of Arts in International Relations,** May 2005 GPA: 3.7/4.0 Dean's List 8/8 semesters

Honors: Academic Merit Scholarship (2001-2005), Social Science Research Grant (2004), Department of International Relations Bennett Scholar (2004), Honors Program Scholarship (2002-2004), Clarence Schock (SICO) Foundation Scholar (2001), Gretchen Schwartz Memorial Scholarship (2001), Phi Beta Kappa National Honor Society (2005), Alpha Lambda Delta National Honor Society (2003-2005)

**Activities:** Blue Hen Ambassador, Honors Program Peer Writing Tutor, Department of Political Science Teaching Assistant, Model United Nations